uh I certainly probably wouldn't have
gone poking at the great firewall
personally I've never been to China but
I'd like to go at least once before I do
that um
[Music]
[Applause]
all righty y'all time for another threat
Locker lockdown story okay picture this
you're on an internal pen test and you
finally got a foothold on a Target
machine you've reached the point where
it's time to Snoop around a little bit
and see if you can find these little
juicy pieces of information that allow
you to Pivot deeper into the network you
open up the desktop and what do you see
but what every hacker loves to see
password.txt file you type cat or type
or whatever it is on Windows to get the
contents of that file and just as you
press enter the shell drops no why did
the shell
drop that my friend was a threat Locker
Canary file and that machine is now on
complete lockdown you're burnt end scene
I know I know I know that was traumatic
you all but I had to let you know what
kind of things threat Locker detect is
doing to hackers so if you or a loved
hacker has experienced trauma at the
hands of threat Locker systems please
call the threat Locker hacker complaint
number at 833 292
7732 all right guys let's go back to the
show all righty man here we go chains
out ready to roll get the Chain Gang
going I finally I finally got one
yesterday and I'm feeling it you know it
it brings an extra level of confidence I
think to the it's really it's really
bringing your your Florida out oh is it
really all right I well the hair is
extra curly today too so I'm feeling it
I'm feeling it yeah yeah all right man
well this week we have a lot of C
research that has has hit the twitters
has hit the uh the bug Bounty scene geez
where do we where do we
start um well do you want to start with
the asdot research because that was
pretty crazy yeah that one that one is
crazy for sure every once in a while I
there's like you know again there's like
a tweet from shs and just be like oh
yeah we found this thing it's like how
long are you spend did you spend looking
at this cuz this feel like months of
research yeah and he was just casually
about it too like I think he he he
tweeted out the first time he's like um
uh on the 27th of this of September or
something like that we're going to drop
some crazy [__] and then he did um and
and so yeah dude I mean having read
through the whole thing it's like I
don't understand
why the the great firewall of China
would implement this this way this seems
so such like a weird thing to do um but
the tldr of the situation is essentially
anything that routes through China from
a DNS perspective is getting DNS
poisoned um
and essentially any keyword if it
contains a specific keyword like web
proxy ID or um I think they listed like
700 something keywords at the at the
bottom of the research um then if that
is in the subdomain of this any DNS
resolution it will just resolve it to
like a random IP address a set of random
IP addresses and um you know the the
where the rubber meets the road with
that is that uh there there are
vulnerabilities on hosted on these IP
addresses right so one of them is
vulnerable to a c panel xss and one of
them or several of them are actually um
uh IP addresses that point towards a a
proxy provider that I I can't pull out
of my brain right now which which one
was it was it like prox
proxify uh fastly fastly that's it yeah
that's it um yeah fastly and and so you
can go on there and just register that
domain and uh and to your account and
almost pull like what a subdomain
takeover would look like um in these
sort of scenarios so it lots of domains
are affected and uh and it's crazy that
they implemented it this way yeah I mean
it's it's really wild um I guess it's
one of those attack services that like
most people probably just don't touch
out of a variety of reasons uh I
certainly probably wouldn't have gone
poking at the great firewall personally
uh I've never been to China but I like
to go at least once before I do that
um so uh it's just uh you know props to
the asset note team because um I don't
know if I would ever step foot in China
again that being said super super cool
research yeah yeah I think I think also
you know that
they they shows their commitment to
their their uh customers because they're
like yes so we unboarded this this
customer and they had some stuff in
China and then we realized like what is
all this garbage that we're seeing right
like we have to fix this for them and
then they went down that rabbit hold of
fixing it for them and that's how they
found that this that this weird Edge
case was happening right um so yeah I
think I think it's I think it's really
solid and I think that that shows you
know when you have such a mass amount of
data like aote has you you see these
anomalies uh if you're looking closely
and um and you're able to find cool
pieces of research like this yeah yeah
absolutely yeah and it seems like Eric
as well uh today is new contributed
pretty significantly to This research he
he dropped a bunch of um keywords and
know IPS associated with um the ways
that you can poison these these various
domains um so now that there's a there's
a whole list and there's also what I
think a lot of people might have missed
and I they they put a little um
disclaimer at the top of the article now
but I don't think that was there in the
beginning is that at the very bottom of
this article so if you go to like dnsp
poison. comom it'll redirect to the
article um there's like a little tool
and you can just enter a domain and
it'll be like yes that domain is
vulnerable here's your xss you know
here's your here's your atto you know
that sort of thing um and so uh I think
I think it's cool that they implemented
that right into the blog um and I
definitely think it would be it' be cool
to see somebody take this off you know
off the the web interface here put it
into a command line tool and spray it
across all the programs like I'm sure
Eric is doing you know if Eric was
involved in the research then there's
definitely some large scale Automation
in place but definitely applicable in a
more wide environment
yeah I definitely do uh this is
something I've seen more and more in
like recent blog posts as like an
interactive element so to speak or just
like uh you know like a form or a table
or something that you can like input a
value into and it'll like interactively
tell you if it's affected or whatever um
and it seems like a a nice way to make
sort of that that research more tangible
it's it's more of f for sure you know
and um and I think that with I've
actually noticed that with and talked a
little bit about this on the Pod a
couple weeks ago but with cursor and
with some of these other systems that
make it so easy to build out these like
pretty simple poc's and stuff like that
I think this will become a lot more
common because now I don't have to sit
there write all this little CSS to make
it actually look decent I can just say
like do this and then call this function
and it just plops it out and and that
really that's really helpful yeah yeah
for sure um well speaking of pcc's um
there was this project discovery
uh block post about um there was a ruby
samle bypass I think the one was
actually in Ruby samel right like the
core Library well I don't know core but
like the library Ruby saml that is a
used by a lot of different things
including gitlab um so uh it's it's you
know samel is one of those things what
was the the samel ramble the S ramble
the episode what was that episode like
48 or something like that it was a while
ago but as we have talked about before
samle is very
very finicky it's easy to shoot yourself
in the foot there's a lot of
verification and signing and hashing and
all these sorts of things that you need
to be doing properly in the correct
order in a very specific way if you do
it in the wrong way or you skip a step
or you make an assumption then it's very
easy for an attacker to smuggle uh
malicious SLE payload through through
your server and do you know potentially
really really drastic um you know off
bypasses that kind of stuff so yeah
episode episode 46 was what that was
when I just absolutely lost my mind on
samel and I just like deep dived that
and then just dumped it all on you guys
um so if you're interested in in
learning a little bit more about it
episode 46 for that but um yeah dude I
think this is really quality research
coming out of project Discovery and you
know we see we see um a lot of great
tools obviously come out from from
Project discovery which is which is
great um but I think it's also really
cool that they have this research
division where where finding you know
Zer days and writing them up and
integrating them into the tools and you
know releasing nuclei um templates for
these these exploits so um yeah Maj
major props to um the team over there
the the takeaway from for me on this one
was a couple things but primarily the
the biggest one was that when you're
doing this samel signature validation
there has to be some way for you to
select the nodes that you are you you
need to be hashing and you need to be
check the signature on right and that is
typically done via XPath and um and when
you're when you're using XPath obviously
you're you're selecting from a uh an XML
document um and as XML we we all know
from from you know learning about HTML
parsers and XML parsers and all this
sort of thing that that is a very um
Shifty environment there's like
mutations that will occur from from one
to the other um and I think trusting
expath to do the selection correctly uh
is is definitely something you have to
do in order to be able to to select the
elements out but I think there's a lot
of wiggle room there and if you can get
it to select the incorrect element like
it did in this scenario um then clearly
a lot of damage can be done uh so that's
something whenever I review code for
saml stuff in the future the the one
takeaway that I'm going to have in my
brain from this from this blog post is
like investigate how they're doing their
X paath selections and see if you can if
there's any wiggle room in there yeah
yeah well and I think it's more
critically than that it's like something
as simple as an xox selection you might
think is
not anything complicated but you it's
it's a kind of a complex functionality
when you think about it right like
you're you're taking a blob and you're
selecting a key from it and in the case
of XML there's no guarantee that those
keys are unique or what order they're in
or anything like that so when the
library is naively just saying hey give
me this element by this
key you know what if there's two of it
what if you know what you know how does
it select it later on how does it
compare against it can I put one in a
different order can I put one in a
different place so I think that
something as simple as that it's
important to just not take that
functionality for granted and there's
probably other instances of things that
are very very similar to this whether
it's
JavaScript uh query selectors or css
query selectors um or XML
or beautiful soup or you know there's a
ton of different ways that like X paath
in these query selector type behaviors
is used all over the place um and I
think you know maybe some creative
research could be done around how these
things are working and whether or not
there's other pitfalls around you know
that selection process where you might
just be like oh give me that element but
you know sort of like this like double
use or use after free type mentality
where it's like you know you're using
you're selecting an element in one place
but like you select it somewhere else it
might come out different M yeah and I
think that um that there's that just to
even take the principle higher like you
were saying that selection in general I
think is is tricky because there's
there's a lot of a lot of these
algorithms for Signature validation or
whatever are really vetted and are
pretty hardcore but they a single point
of failure would be where they are
getting their information from right um
and so I think that's that's a great
principle to take away the the other
thing that I was reading through this
and I was like yeah man this is just
kind of weird
right after I say all the signature
algorithms are vetted and everything uh
is that you know XML or the way that
samle does the signature validation is
the whole samle response is not signed
it's it's the assertions right and then
those assertions are are um are signed
or are hashed and then that that list of
hashes essentially is then signed right
and that's how the validation occurs
right um so in this scenario you know
what what they're able to do is they're
able to smuggle in an assertion by um
putting in a a hash in a specific spot
that that isn't a part of the signature
right so it's not something that's going
to invalidate the signature and when
they check to see if the assertion
mashes the hash it does because you can
just hash it yourself right um and then
when they go to check the signature
because that that um hash that they
defined is not actually a part of that
signature then the signature still
matches because uh nothing inside the
signature was tampered with right um so
it if there there's a little bit of a
disconnect there right with with how
saml samle is is being validated there's
like this signed list of hashes and not
everything in the the body of the saml
response is actually being signed so
there's some wiggle room for you to
sneak in various elements and and hijack
selectors and that sort of thing without
actually affecting the signature the
Integrity of the signature in that in
that response yeah for sure and I I just
find it very interesting in general like
anything that's like sort of like self
encapsulated that that that should kind
of raise some red flags where like
there's a signature inside the message
but it's excluded from the signature
itself you know what I mean like it's a
signature that represents the message
that inside of it's kind of it's kind of
strange Behavior because CC right like
on the on like the server side
like it has to remove that and like
calcul like yeah it's it's just a weird
it seems a little bit over engineered
and so again I can definitely see how it
would be possible to yourself in the
foot yeah so the there's XA so two
things in my little samle samle trick
you know folder in my brain right now is
is the XPath thing and then there's also
the xslt thing that we talked about in
the SLE ramble episode where you know
you're actually applying these
transformations to um the the XML as
it's being parsed um in various
different parts of the the uh XL
document might be being parsed at at
different places in different ways so
those Transformations can create
mismatch uh mismatches um and so those
are definitely two things that I'm going
to keep up in in the top of my head X
paath and um xslt for for parsing um SLE
stuff yeah for sure so there's um
there's a there like I said there's a p
um you know speaking of PC so you know
they of course project Discovery
released um a nuclear template for this
bug that will scan for it I think I
don't know if it only looks for gitlab
instances cuz that's what was affected
or it just like kind of looks
generically across the board yeah it
seems like gitlab yeah I think it's just
just gitlab by the looks of the quy but
um you know that's a you know if you're
using nuclear already then I'm your
template should auto update so you'll
probably already get this automatically
but yeah you know it's definitely some
interesting research um and um G laab is
not the only the only application that
uses s yeah yeah
so before this episode Joel was like ah
Justin can we delay this a little bit I
need to go look at something um so that
that's great I love that um but yeah
definitely more more widely applicable
yeah I got to beat the publication of
this pod with the I'm GNA have to look
right after this yeah yeah you got to go
man um yeah so that that one's pretty
solid uh definitely definitely a cool
write up there and I and I think um a
lot of this
too you know they they they narrow this
down to this specific Library as well
and it takes a lot of set setup and it
takes a lot of introspection to get um
um you know to get these libraries sort
of isolated away from like gitlab or
isolated away from you know whatever
piece of software that you're attacking
but I think if you can isolate them out
and just focus specifically on finding
vulnerabilities in the library um that
can be very widely applicable and I
think that's another area where AI can
really help a lot you could just say
like hey um you know cursor could you
please like stand up a sample SLE
application you that uses this library
right and you know it it's ingested all
the docks it understands how how to
dockerize things and stuff like that and
if it can spin up that library and give
it a you know give you a playground
where you can you know have a debugger
in there and actually see okay well when
it does this XPath selection it's
grabbing this you know um I think that
that I think that will be really helpful
for security researchers as well because
there's so much friction that comes
along with getting your environment set
up you know your VMS your Enterprise
software stuff um it just I think I
think there's a lot of room for
improvement there yeah yeah and I like
well two two funny things one I find it
very amusing that the uh the nuclei
template itself uses xath
selectors um so hopefully they hopefully
they didn't write a bug in there uh but
secondly like from unrelated to that
from like the you know the sort of like
setup process like you said like yeah
I've been setting up
a source control application and let me
just say it is quite a process okay not
only does it need an insane amount of
resources like literally I I spun up
this software and it started and it was
like
ah I only have 40 gigs of RAM I need 60
minimum 60 60 gigabytes of RAM I like
Jesus oh no dude so it's just one of
those things that like uh you know it's
a bit of a learning curve for sure I had
to set up a bunch of uh DNS records and
all sorts of like things that
um aren't exactly the most glorious
stuff to set up that's for sure um but
you know once you get through that
barrier then uh you know there's lots of
research you can unlock afterwards
so yeah I think um I think that other
researchers aren't doing that as much
either right so we've seen time and time
again that if you take the time you set
up the software you get yourself a nice
environment you're going to find so much
more because uh it's not as hardened and
I think a lot of a lot of newer people
um they they they will shy away from
that because they don't have the
confidence that the path they're going
down is the right way and instead
they'll keep slamming their head into
very very very hardened scope uh because
it's just you know right on the surface
because that's what everybody looks at
and uh it's really you're kind of
shooting yourself in the foot with that
I think um yeah I will say like you know
that grit during when you come across
frustrating things is like I definitely
just see it more as a okay okay if I'm
hitting this wall every other researcher
has also so if I push through that then
that narrows the you know the
competition for sure
100% hey guys our sponsor project
Discovery has dropped a new tool in
collaboration with Google's own Mandan
team called TLD finder okay picture the
SubFinder but for top level domains did
I say anymore check it
out um all right let's uh let's let's
jump around a little bit on this um
we've got the
I don't know how how much do we want to
talk about this this mediatech wi-fi
chipset exploit because yeah I mean we
could speak about it briefly so I mean
so so basically there was a cve um in
the
mediatech chipset certain mediatech
chipsets mediatech is a chip
manufacturer they make um a lot of Wi-Fi
chips and they're used in a variety of
different Android
devices um and iot devices and um a
bunch of their chipsets
um include including ones that I think
are used as some routers were vulnerable
to a buffer overflow I think it was um
it's quite complicated I mean it's one
of those lowlevel like C++
vulnerabilities like straight up so
there's a really interesting indepth
write up that was uh provided by coffin
secc uh on their blog about you know how
it works and what's affected and the
whole background and Discovery process
and the payload and everything it's very
very good um I don't think we need to
get into the rchain specifics yeah I was
going to say as I'm scrolling through
this I'm like you know we do our best to
condense the material OD critical
thinking into the audio medium but you
kind of can't just start reading out
like exploits like this uh on on the
podcast but I do think so Joel maybe you
can Enlighten us with with regards to
this like um clearly there are some
pretty well formed exploits in there um
what how would we how would we apply
these are are we are we going to you
know should we attack iot devices that
that um are we looking at mobile stuff
we looking at iot devices what kind of
stuff will this affect yeah mo mobile
and iot I know that there's at least one
iot device out there on the market that
uses a mediate Tech chip although I
believe it's a newer version than these
so I'm not 100% sure if it's vulnerable
it's something I've been meaning to test
um but that being said uh there is a
list of uh affected known chipsets and
software versions I think it was also
some like something to do with like the
SDK obviously the right it manifests
itself in like a software um thing so
it's not like uh purely a hardware
vulnerability it just affects certain
chipsets um I guess based on the SDK
that SDK that it uses or something but
yeah I think like definitely if you see
something that's using mediatech
especially in the 7,000 or 6,000 Series
M Mt chipsets probably would at least
try the exploit there's I'm pretty sure
there's just a python script on this
GitHub
rep to test it out so um yeah the other
thing uh that's interesting about this
um is that it was found with fuzzing um
and fuzzing is something that I've spent
a little bit of time recently looking
into and I think every once in a while
it kind of like posts his head back up
um but I think fuzzing is still
definitely a very very useful technology
and it's not going away anytime soon
this fuzzer that was used specifically
for TCP andp fuzzing it's called fotron
and it's like designed as a network
fuzzer so this was found essentially
blackbox by fuzzing network uh traffic
or packets or something to this chipset
until it crashed and then was developed
into a full exploit which is awesome
yeah that is pretty rad I think I think
once again something that requires a lot
of setup right um and one thing that
I've been kind of toying with Joel is
like how do we you know how do we H in
this position as as people that are in
the community researchers and and run
this podcast and kind of have a little
bit of a platform how do we encourage
and help
people put in the time and and get
better Roi to do deeper research like
this right where you have to set up like
this fuzzing harness and you got to like
detect all of these crashes and blah
blah blah right um that's something that
I'm I'm continuing to to to Noodle on
but I think it'd be really cool at some
point to do um grants or something like
that uh and and have people you know
just decide okay you know the mediatech
chipsets are are very widely used you
know and it would make sense for us to
have um you know a Docker thing set up
where we could fuzz this more simply or
or um that sort of thing so I think it's
really cool to see people take the Deep
dive on that and uh fuzzing is
definitely an area that I I can improve
on I I I don't I don't even really use
it that much in web I I do sometimes but
um clearly you know at at this binary
protocol level um especially in light of
some of the exploits we've seen lately
in in live hacking events um there
there's a lot a lot to be gained
there well on that topic of
um fuzzing and you know e finishing
exploits and all that kind of stuff
websites whatever there's a lot of
connections here oh my god there there's
two things that uh that were in the list
that were really good so there's um the
first one is this uh this kaido plugin
from tur
turn.js
t24 tur um on Twitter X
sorry
um so basically it's just an AI tool
that will generate wordless for you I
believe so you basically just say here's
a class of bug um and I don't even think
you give it any other input than that
right it's just here's a class of bug
and it just goes here's a list of
payloads well so there there there are
some some AI things that we'll address a
little bit later down in in that section
but this one I think is more
specifically Al just for generating word
list based off of a a a set of of word
list you know the SEC list um tools from
from Daniel Meisler and essentially just
management of those word lists within
kaido and I think I think it's great to
see that that released and out there um
but switching to the AI vein um the the
the kaido plugin that I really wanted to
to talk about that does AI just so well
is the uh is bex's kaido 403 bypasser
plugin right um and I think this was
actually motivated by the episode that
we released on brainstorming proxy
plugins and Beck sort of took that and
really just implemented it perfectly man
so when I see this I am so happy right
so click click on this link dude click
on this link and go to the GitHub repo
and look at the um look at the demo that
he has on there right um it it it brings
up this interphase and it's the perfect
hybrid
of having automation that you can
customize and build your in your own way
right cuz what we talked about on the
episode was like okay 4 or3 bypasser
like that's cool but but I don't have
enough introspection into what it's
actually doing for me to trust it so I'm
still going to sit there and fuzz
manually right and and like you know
play around with stuff and tweak stuff
and that sort of thing right um what
this thing does and this is the
beautiful part of it is it allows you to
use AI to say okay um I want to try uh
these are the things I want to put in my
403 bypasser my customized version of
the for or3 bypasser I want to put all
of the different requests I want to put
a um you know a semicolon slash at this
path index I want to do this and this
and this and then the AI will
automatically generate the code and give
you a test interface where you can test
to sh to ensure that that method is
being implemented the way that you want
it to be implemented and then save it
into your scan templates for the 403
bypasser right um so and then when you
press scan it'll say okay trying your
HTP method trick trying your you know uh
semicolon SL trick you know and then you
can go through and you can see the
different different um outputs for each
one of those things that you would try
um and it's it's it's extremely low
friction because you're just using
natural language to tell the AI to
generate the code which gets loaded into
the template and it's very high
integrity because you can still see
everything that's being checked and have
assurance that oh I don't have to go
back there and manually check this
because I can just see it right here and
I just I just I love that I love that so
much because um it it's something that I
can trust and it's something that has so
low friction for me to implement and
then have saved off for the future any
anytime I need to do four or three
bypasses in the future yeah absolutely
yeah and um we're finally getting now to
a point as well with the with this the
plugins and stuff like the ecosystem
within kaido that it's some it's getting
a lot better to manage stuff I just went
in and I can now update plugins manually
or like automatically I guess like you
just go into the tab and you just click
update and everything is much more
integrated now
so finally finally I mean and there's a
burp I mean if you look at burp and you
look at how long burp is been around and
you look how long it's taken for some
things to happen on there versus how
things are CH changing on kaido you know
we F boil off for kaido it's it's a good
product it is and and and there's lots
of evolution happening in that ecosystem
I'm working on a plugin right now that
I'm super excited to release um
hopefully we'll be able to release it
within the next month or so but um
there's a lot of Dev going on right now
and I'm getting very familiar with the
kaido uh apis and I think um i' also the
kaido team is is uh here's a I'm just
leak leaking this you know as I do uh
Kyo team is putting a lot of effort
right now into the the dev ecosystem um
in in Q4 um and so I think as we're
going to see a lot of really really nice
to haves come into place um and that
make it really easy to Dev front-end and
backend plugins in kaido lots of um lots
of automation surrounding how do we get
like a starter kit up and rolling how do
we you know just have all the
documentation in one spot how do we use
AI to supplement that and say like hey
you know this is actually how it should
be implemented and that sort of thing um
it's just I'm very excited for it this
upcoming quarter there's going to be a
lot of progress there and I think it's
going to result in an explosion of inov
um in in the in the plugin Arena which
would be very ex one one thing we still
got to solve though is like how how do
we I mean it's that that age-old problem
with open source stuff is like how do we
continue to give incentives to people
that that are developing these plugins
and I think one of the things that kind
of sucks about the the bug Bounty
community and the security community in
general is we don't love to support uh
you know financially a lot of these
projects and that we use um and so I
think I'll just give another shout out
because I support Bex on on GitHub and
you know give the use the G GitHub
subscriber feature um and I think if
you're using if you're using plugins if
you're using um stuff like that
especially if it's directly leading to
monetary game for you through bug Bounty
then maybe like Chuck 25 bucks to your
to your uh you know friendly plugin
developer because that will do a lot for
their their motivation to continue to
develop their
plugin yeah yeah absolutely absolutely
um all right man we got a couple more
things here on the list um we got the oh
this one was really cool so um CSP
bypass.com did you see
this yeah yeah so that was the other one
I was going to bring up was uh CSP
bypass.com this was
from so Ren pek you reny pek yeah yeah
so reny pek I don't well it's on GitHub
right so yeah it's just like oh my God
it was updated 42 minutes ago so awesome
um yeah so there's basically just a list
of CSV bypasses in a in a CSV it's
nothing even that crazy
um and um yeah it's uh it's just a
collection of CSV PP passes and I guess
you just if are trying to bypass CSP and
you're like I need you know there's that
CSP tool that that one that everybody
knows the one from Google the CSP
evaluator and it's like so close to
being useful because you'll go and you
put your whole CSP in there and it'll be
like hey there's this domain on
youtube.com that's vulner to CSP and
you're like
Great's go what is it yeah and it's like
I don't know it just is We're not gonna
tell you that we're not gonna tell you
so this is that yeah this is that last
step right of you know so you go csb bu
bypasses you go youtube.com and hey
there you go script Source youtube.com/
anded Mark callback equals alert one
yeah and there's your CSP P pass YouTube
so this is super super helpful one of
those uh those tools you just throw in
your back pocket and uh I think it's
been good to see the community come
around it as well right like like there
have been a lot of community
contributions people going back through
all their reports and like grabbing all
the CSP bypasses that they've ever used
and lo loading them into this um
the the thing is with this the there's a
couple things that I that I would like
to say with regards to this right like
obviously it's awesome and I'm so glad
that we have it um some of these are not
actual you know bypasses right uh they
they are
Json uh Json P call back interfaces
right and some of them don't have even
the ability to use like a DOT right um
because we saw that research I think it
was related to Wordpress related stuff
where um you know it is possible for you
to exploit a a CSP related um or a CSP
bypass of sorts just using a Json P call
back functionality by by hijacking the
do click function um and and you can
essentially say like if you're able to
uh provide a arbitrary length callback
function and that callback function can
contains dots you can say you know
window. parent. child. child. child.
child. you know whatever find the delete
Account button doclick and because um
you know JavaScript will take any
parameters you know that are in there it
just doesn't care about the parameters
it'll just click the button and delete
your account or whatever right or do
like an O authorization or something
like that if it's on the same origin um
and and so you know definitely
categorizing Json P related
functionality is is massively helpful um
but I did go through here and I was
looking at some of them and like some of
these don't even have like dots you
can't even put a dot you can't put a
slash you can't do a function call um
it's just you know the typical Json P
call back interface which actually isn't
super helpful uh as far as I know um so
definitely something nice to have have
would be to categorize each of these by
like ability by flexibility or like
maybe what character set they support um
uh in the Json P callback and then um
also um the other thing that that I that
I had with regards to this is it would
be really cool to combine CSP evaluator
and this right where you can say okay
here are all the domains in my CSP which
of these domains match a known bypass um
so I think that's some pretty easy Dev
work to do I think we'll probably see it
at some point come into this uh
especially since this has been open
sourced um so someone should probably
definitely go in there and like build in
that parser and then just compare it to
the list of all the bypasses that are
done yeah absolutely I mean I think this
would be a good opportunity to I mean
you could even make another tool out of
just tying these things together or
maybe the to the tool developers could
uh have a little Discord chat and
combine or you know integrate
functionality with each other but
definitely there there's sort of an easy
win here where at minimum as a hacker
you could manually use both of these
tools together and if you want to
streamline your process you could
automate them together and if you want
to streamline everybody else's process
you can release that yeah yeah for sure
um all right so actually I probably
should have clustered this one with the
other one um but let me I'm going to
jump down to this like arbitrary read
right on uh llama.com
it one is relevant to AI stuff which is
very um very hot right now and I think
that I've used llama multiple times and
I think if anybody's interested in doing
offline AI stuff they're familiar with
this um yeah and this there's a pretty
serious vulnerability in uh the Llama
server the RPC server and it was very
odd because it almost looked intentional
like essentially this RPC server which
is unoth was exposing
Primitives where you could essentially
Supply memory addresses and and just
allocate you know onto the Heap and read
from specific like you could literally
give it a memory address and it would
you know read from that and it's like
what um and it's so wild yeah so this
this it was really interesting because
the the guy that did the write up on it
side quest um I was watching some of it
because it's a very good example for me
a as a as a primarily web Hunter
um how this sort of exploitation process
works once you've established The
Primitives because um the RPC protocol
is essentially The Primitives that you
would normally need to trigger these
exploits right and normally you've got
to go find an arbitrary read an
arbitrary write that sort of thing the
RPC protocol was pretty much just
exposing that um so it it the process
was him taking this you know python
crafting this python file to use these
RPC Primitives to trigger code execution
and it was was like it's like an hour
long you know an hour and some change um
and I think it's it's a really cool
example of that exploitation without
having to find that extra layer of like
all right how do I not crash it and like
how do I isolate these specific um
Primitives uh and then build the exploit
so definitely a cool piece of work there
yeah you know this reminds me of um
early on in my bug Bounty career one of
the first bugs that I found was a RPC
server B uh in a crypto project and if
you don't know a lot of crypto projects
they use this thing called the Json RPC
it's yeah kind of similar thing but
that's like how you would like talk with
your wallet and stuff and there was this
RPC call called
delete and literally you would call it
and it would just delete the entire
server wallet and it I was
like I don't know why exists but it's
there and like yeah they were like oh
wow thanks for catching that like we
don't know why was there like yeah dude
that's that's crazy I think there's a
lot of stuff hiding in these non hgp
related protocols and it's scary to try
to investigate them for a lot of people
but um I think when you take take the
dive it's it's very friendly I and just
just to quote some of the the stuff from
this this YouTube video you know he's
looking at this protocol and he's like
yeah it's just like you know one one
integer is like a is like the what call
you're going to do and then there's like
the the message length and then the
message and that's it you know it's just
a very simple binary protocol that took
like five lines of code for him to
implement you know the send the send
call function um and and so I think it's
not as scary as
everyone maybe I shouldn't project it to
everyone as many as as I think it could
be and as many I think web P pentesters
believe it to be um yeah to actually
dive deep on this stuff um and I just I
I no I mean it goes back to that like
that barrier thing right of you know
everybody every hacker is hits the same
barrier that you're hitting whether it's
setting up the software learning the
documentation whatever and if you decide
that you're going to push through that
and you're going to learn through and
you're going to grit and you know head
down and do it then you you get past
where everybody else stopped yeah yeah
for sure um the the other little
takeaway that I wanted to to talk about
on this topic was I think so and this is
just very very wide congestion but I was
listening to the Lex Freedman podcast on
um that they did recently with the
cursor AI team and uh it was very
interesting because they were talking
about optimizing stuff with the llms at
a very low level um and then I I just
you know the next day saw this where
it's like okay you've got this pretty
well-respected um you know
llm entity here uh that is exposing
these Primitives to an RPC you know via
RPC so I think you know I'll just throw
this conjecture out there I think some
of these llm related things may in in in
the pursuit of performance may start
exposing some some much lower level um
functionality via some of these
protocols uh because I know that that's
what the cursor team was talking about
is optimizing at a much lower level um
and and then we we see this right here
with llama as well um so when you're
invest so I think the way that I've
approached AI related targets at this
point has been a lot of like you know
almost like red teaming the AI sort of
approach right and that's sure surely
that is necessary as agents become more
prevalent and you actually weaponize
these these uh llm models to to you know
do stuff but um I think if we want to
take a a more technical approach which
is very attractive to me because of the
wishy-washy nature of AI like I don't
really like red teaming AI because it's
just so wishy-washy um if we want to
take a more technical approach then we
can look deeper and deeper and see if
they're exposing any of these lower
level Primitives that might be used for
optimization of the llm to get snappier
response times like you see in cursor
yeah I will say like one of the things
that bothers me a lot about testing with
AI and like trying to do adversarial
stuff with AI is that you can get down a
rabbit hole where it gets like stuck
with all this context that you've been
testing with for whatever and if you
just make a new chat it can behave
completely different and like it's like
as you know a reset basically where you
can sort of
re path it to in the direction that you
want simply just based on the fact that
it doesn't have the context from the
previous attempts and that can be very
very frustrating to go back and forth
with I think yeah yeah absolutely it
can yeah I I I think I don't know if I'm
ready to say it on the I guess I'll say
it on the podcast just because that's
how I do but I think definitely within
the next year too I would like to
experiment more with this lower level
exploitation stuff um I think I've spent
a lot of time on web and I think there
is overlap between web and some of this
this um you know binary exploitation
stuff uh that that it would be really
helpful for me to be able to utilize my
web skills to be able to interact with
some of these sort of things and
understand what's happening a little bit
better at that lower level um so I think
I'm going to go back after this episode
and rewatch this this exploitation video
um and and see what I can take away from
it because I I think this is a really
cool example of of how you can do that
yeah yeah for sure um all right last one
that we had on the list for for today
was uh just a helpful little WAFF bypass
that I came across um and this was under
an article T entitled xss WAFF bypass
one payload for all and uh this is by a
guy named edra um and I'm looking
through here and the there's some
there's some interesting bypasses in
here so definitely check it out
obviously they're going to get whacka
mold you know like like the whole um wff
bypass game
goes uh but I I liked the principle
of essentially weaponizing encodings
against waffs themselves because waffs
by Nature need to be able to deal with
various uh layers of encoding because
they don't know what they're dealing
with on the backside of them
right uh on the back side of the uh the
WAFF um and and so this whole concept of
using uh different levels of encoding
with the same entity in this case a a
double quote I think is is pretty
attractive so the the exploit that he
released was or or the the bypass that
was released was um x equals and then
double quote and then a quote entity in
HTML and then another double quote and
then you know an on handle or whatever
um and so they're they're mixing that
you know traditional just double quote
plus the HTML in coding to create a
mismatch in perception from the server
and and the the WF thinks okay this is
an X attribute and then an attribute
that starts with double quote and then
goes to on error right whereas actually
the the middle piece is actually
encapsulated inside the HTML attribute
and the onerror definition is U is it
its own attribute itself which will
trigger um so it's just trying to take
these principles and and bring them up
to a higher level and say what can we
what can we learn from this specific Waf
bypass um is is that uh creating an odd
uh number of these these specific
entities right you've got double quote
double quote double quote three um and
then sort of creating that mismatch
between various HTML entities encodings
that sort of thing is is pretty widely
applicable I think yeah yeah I I mean
and again you can just file this one
into the the the notebook of bypasses or
put it includeed into the AI script in
the 403 bypasser whatever you know like
there's there's a ton of different um
there's a ton of different little
bypasses and little I don't know gadgets
coming out now that are so useful to
have in the back pocket um I will say
it's almost getting to a point now where
I need some way to like organize them
and just test them all at the same time
so I think those extensions that are
like you know 403 bypasser and that kind
of stuff that do a lot of different
tests at once against a single Target
are pretty useful because it makes it so
I don't have to remember so many
individual things yeah and and the this
article contains three uh bypasses for
impera Amazon WF and Akamai um that all
utilize this specific functionality and
and as we I think also just lately with
shazzar and with some of the other
research that's been coming out
surrounding HTML entities I think HTML
entities in particular as in encoding uh
are are pretty helpful because there's
so many ways to represent the same
character even even with these like sort
of um double character uh ones that
we've seen where it's like okay you get
like a less than sign and some junk you
know that sort of thing um I think will
be very helpful for for bypassing wafs
in the in the
future um all right man I think that's
that's all I had I got this you know I'm
going to push this next one to to next
week so I think that's all I had on the
list you got anything else before we
close off this one I think that was it
dude all right GG peace that's the
Pod and that's a wrap on this episode of
critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb Dosh
show/ Discord join the Discord there's
lots of great conversations and chats
going on over there and if you want to
support the show there's the Discord
subscriber tiers which give you access
to master classes amas hack alongs
exclusive scripts and an exclusive chat
Channel with us we'll see you there
[Music]